Guide to the Melchior Palyi Papers 1915-1970
University of Chicago Library
- Series V: Books and Pamphlets
  - Subseries 2: French-language Books and Articles
    - Articles, Philip Cortney, "L'Or, le Dollar et l'Economie Américaine," 1970 Harry D. Gideonse, "Etude Générale du Programme Roosevelt," 1934 Yves Simon. La Campagne d'Ethiopie et la Pensée Politique Française, 1936 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - H. Rheinstrom. L'influence du régime national-socialiste sur le droit privé allemand, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 3: English-language Books and Articles
    - Collection of University of Chicago Round Table transcripts, "If Europe Paid its Debts," "If Germany Wins," "Hitler's Economic Motives," "The Economic Struggle for South America," "Can Capitalism Survive the War?" "Is Russia Losing in Finland?" 1939-1940 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - A World to Live In - Published collection of writings on the problems of reconstruction after the end of World War II, 1942 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Bretton Woods Agreements Act, "Hearings before the Committee on Banking and Currency," 1945 (Box 24, Folder 6-7)
    - Bretton Woods Agreements Act, "Hearings before the Committee on Banking and Currency," 1945 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Publications, Institute of Business and Economic Problems. A Series of Lectures, 1953 Proceedings of the International Trade Institute, 1954 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Proceedings of conference held by the Russian anti-Communist weekly Possev and titled "Towards Freedom," 1956 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Publications, Proceedings of conference held by The National Industrial Conference Board, "Economic Concentration Measures: Uses and Abuses," 1957 The Swiss Economy in 1969, ca. 1970 James W. Angell, "Gold, Banks and the New Deal," 1934 C. Bresciani-Turroni, "The "Purchasing Power Parity" Doctrine," 1934 C. Bresciani-Turroni, "Inductive Verification of the Theory of International Payments," undateda C. Bresciani-Turroni, "Monetary Policy and 'Full Employment,'" 1957 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Publications, Frederick George Conolly, "Reflections on the Cheap-Money Policy, Particularly in England," 1939 Joseph Dach, "Tax Aspects of Inflation: A Study in Monetary Nominalism," 1960 Christopher Emmet and Fritz Baade, "Destruction at Our Expense: How Dismantling Factories in Germany Helps Inflation in the United States and Sabotages the Marshall Plan," 1947 John Exter, "The Gold Losses," 1962 Allan G.B. Fisher, "Full Employment and Income Inequality," 1946 Carlos Garcia-Mata and Felix I. Shaffner, "Solar and Economic Relationships, A Preliminary Report," 1949 Michael A. Halperin, "Monetary Internationalism and its Crisis," 1938 F.A. von Hayek, "Economics and Knowledge," 1937 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Publications, Ferdinand A. Hermens, "Potsdam or Peace: The Choice is Before Us," 1946 Theodore J. Kreps, "Consumption: A Vast Underdeveloped Economic Frontier," 1941 Harold D. Lasswell and Renzo Sereno, "Governmental and Party Leaders in Fascist Italy," 1937 John H.S. Lee, "Are Science and Religion at Strife?" 1945 Bernhard Menne. The Case of Dr. Bruening, 1937 Walter A. Morton, "Zero Deposit Rate," 1940 Copy of speech addressed by the Honorable Daniel Patrick Moynihan, Counselor to the President, to the Cabinet and Sub-cabinet, sent to Palyi from the White House, correspondence, 1970 A.F.W. Plumptree, "The Role of Interest Rates and Bank Credit in the Economies of the British Dominions," 1939 A.F.W. Plumptree, "The Arguments for Central Banking in the British Dominions," undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Publications, Hollington K. Tong (Ambassador of the Republic of China to the United States). What is Ahead for China: A Collection of Speeches, 1957 Jacob Viner, "Rearmament and International Commercial Policies," 1951 Jacob Viner, "Balanced Deflation, Inflation, or More Depression," 1933 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Subseries IV: Pamphlets
    - Anti-Nazi pamphlets titled "Sozialistische Aktion," 1934-1938 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - German- and English-language collection of pamphlets titled "Deutschland-Berichte der Sozialdemokratischen Partei Deutschlands," 1937-1938 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Two clandestine anti-Hitler pamphlets, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Collection of Information Bulletin magazines published by the Embassy of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, 1943-1947 (Box 26, Folder 4-5)
    - Collection of Soviet war documents published by the Embassy of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, 1943 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Ilya Ehrenburg "We Will Not Forget" (published by the Embassy of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics), 1944 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Collection of English-language pamphlets published by the Embassy of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, 1946-1948 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Russian-language anti-Communist pamphlet, 1952 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Russian-language pamphlet titled "Perezov," 1952 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Volume devoted to Soviet-German battles in World War II, published by the Embassy of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, undated (Box 26, Folder 11)